nremt.org 2012-10-02

# NREMT - PRIVACY POLICY

PRIVACY POLICY

The National Registry of EMTs (NREMT) has adopted the following Privacy Policy applicable to personal information that we may receive related to certification, licensure, and research. 

**Certification, Licensure, and Research**   
We provide national certification services as a service to State licensing and regulatory agencies. These state agencies issue licenses to practice EMS within their respective jurisdiction. We collect and receive personal information during the certification process. We use this information in order to evaluate candidate's ability, to collect payment services, to provide information about individual's certification status to licensing agencies, and to conduct research. Providing personal data is voluntary, but necessary if you wish to receive certification and/or licensure. You may request a waiver of the biometric security procedures for religious or personal reasons by submitting a written appeal to the NREMT at least 14 business days prior to testing. We will handle and treat all personal information collected and received by us in connection with application, examination administration, and certification in the manner outlined in this Privacy Policy. 

  * **Personal Information Collected.** The personal data that we collect or receive in registering a candidate ("you") for certification services will include your: name, address, email address, phone/fax numbers, social security number, credit/debit card information, date of birth, employment information, previous examination history, education information, and disciplinary actions (including, but not limited to, revocations and suspensions).  For candidate verification and identification purposes, we may collect all or part of the information on a government-issued identification number and your mother’s maiden name. When an electronic certification examination is administered to you, we may collect and score your exam responses and then derive a score and generate a report about your professional certification examination results and will report that information to licensing agencies. Depending upon where your examination takes place and the level of exam that you are taking, we may collect your signature, photographic image, and fingerprint digitally when you arrive at an examination center and you may be audio- and video-taped while taking the exam. 

  * **Aggregation of Non-Person-Specific Data.** We may statistically aggregate in non-person-specific form exam performance and other information collected during the certification.  Such aggregated non-person-specific information may be used for quality control/improvement, operations management, security and marketing purposes and to enhance, develop or improve the certification processes, testing services, examinations and related products and services. By applying for certification through us, you give your consent for us to use this non-person-specific aggregated data as outlined above. 

  * **Mailings and Contact.** We may use your email and/or postal address to send you information about your certification status and other information that may be of interest to you professionally.  We may also contact you regarding participation in research projects that are deemed to be of value to the professional community.  You may opt out of receiving information from the NREMT at any time by notifying us in writing or following the opt-out instructions in your electronic profile. 

  * **Transfer of Information to Licensing Agencies.** By applying for certification through us, you give your consent for your personal information (with the exception of your debit/credit card information) to be transmitted by the NREMT to state EMS licensing agencies.  Licensing agencies require this personal data so that they may issue state licenses to practice.  For further information about how the licensing agencies may use your personal information, please contact the state EMS regulatory authority. 

  * **Transfer of Information to Educational Institutions.** By applying for certification through us, you give your consent for your personal information (with the exception of your debit/credit card information) to be transmitted by the NREMT to your educational institution and/or educational program accreditation agency.  Such information may be used for quality control/improvement, operations management, security and marketing purposes and to enhance, develop or improve the educational processes. 

  * **Other Transfer of Information.** In addition to the above circumstances, we may disclose personally identifiable information about you in the following situations: (a) in response to a subpoena, court order or legal process, to the extent permitted and required by law; (b) to protect your security or the security of other persons, consistent with applicable law; (c) for investigation of possible misconduct; or (d) legitimate research purposes.  By applying for National Certification, you give your consent for your personal information to be transmitted in the situations outlined above. 

  * **Public Information.** Since National Certification is part of a health care credentialing process, and the public has the right to verify the qualifications of the individuals providing care, the NREMT considers your certification status to be public information. 

  * **Independent Testing Centers.** NREMT certification examinations are administered through independent testing centers. These centers may provide unrelated services and may collect and use personal data for other purposes under different terms and policies. If you have any questions or concerns about an independent testing center’s collection or use of any of your personal information, please talk to the independent testing center directly. If you have unaddressed concerns about an independent testing center relating to certification, please contact us. 

  * **Information Access and Corrections.** To access and correct the personal information that we have collected under this policy, please contact us in writing. To protect your privacy and security, we will take reasonable steps to verify your identity before granting access or making alterations. 

  * **Research Data.** Data collected or analyzed for research purposes will be handled according to the protocol approved by the Institutional Review Board of the principal investigator for that project.  Depending on the project, this may differ from this Privacy Policy. 

  * **Protection of Personal Information.** We use reasonable precautions to protect personal information from unauthorized use, access, disclosure, alteration or destruction. These precautions include appropriate physical, electronic and managerial procedures. We provide a secured transmission method for the electronic transmission of credit/debit card information. 

  * **Resolution of Concerns.** If you have questions or concerns about this Privacy Policy or how we have handled personal data, please contact us at 1-614-888-4484. If we are unable to satisfactorily address your concerns, you should contact the Data Protection Authority, or other relevant organization, in your area. 

**Information from Children  
** This web site and our certification services are not directed to children or anyone under the age of thirteen (13). NREMT will not, through this web site or through its professional certification examination and administration process, knowingly collect, maintain or use any personally identifiable information about anyone under the age of thirteen (13). 

**Information Received from Internet Service Providers Through This Web Site  
** This web site receives information that is automatically generated by a user’s Internet Service Provider (ISP). This information may include the IP address (a number automatically assigned to a computer by the ISP), the associated URLs, domain types, the browser type used to access our site, the country, state and telephone area code, the location of the ISP’s servers, the pages of our site that the user views during the visit, any search terms entered on this site, and the user’s web site address and email address. This information may be collected for system administration purposes, to gather broad demographic information and to monitor the level of activity on the site. NREMT does not link IP addresses to personally identifiable information; however, we reserve the right to link IP addresses and other information supplied by the ISP to personally identifiable information in order to protect the integrity of our system and for security purposes

**Cookies**   
Cookies are small text files that a web site transfers to your computer’s browser. We use cookies to measure traffic patterns, personalize content and control security. The cookies we use supply non-personally identifiable information, but they may identify your computer, browser and Internet specifications. 

**Transmission of Information  
**The Internet is a global environment. By using this site and sending information to us electronically, you consent to trans-border and international transmission of any data that you may choose to supply us. Information transmissions to this site and emails sent to us may not be secure. Given the inherent operation and nature of the Internet, all Internet transmissions are done at the user’s own risk. 

**Links to Other Sites**   
This site may contain links to other web sites on the Internet. The information practices of those web sites are not covered by this Privacy Policy, but by their own terms and policies, which you should read carefully. These other sites may send their cookies to users, collect data or solicit personal information. This Privacy Policy applies only to information collected or received in connection with certification and license testing. This Privacy Policy is not intended to apply to other web sites, or other types of information which may be subject to different privacy policies. 

**Changes to This Privacy Policy**   
We reserve the right to change the terms of this Privacy Policy from time to time by posting an updated Privacy Policy. We encourage you to review this Privacy Policy periodically for any changes or updates. 

**How to Contact Us**   
If you have any questions or concerns about this Privacy Policy, please contact us at 1 (614) 888-4484. 

Return to Top
